Hi there, this is Curtis Carter and this particular drill is called pro passing and defense.
Again, being a well rounded player, you don't want to be one dimensional so you want to be complete in every way.
Being complete is also knowing how to pass the basketball as a guard and a big guy and playing defense.
Championship teams begin with defense and we're going to play pro defense.
First drill we're going to is a simple chest pass.
I will start slow, I'll go close, medium to the free throw line and back just chest passing.
It?s very important that you have a strong, firm chest pass.
Find the bulls-eye on teammate's chest and hit him right in the middle.
In all aspects of the game when you're passing with the chest pass.
Start up close and the important thing is as you do the chest pass, you want to pass it thumbs down.
Pass it, thumbs down.
And I would also like to say that when you pass the ball, you want to step forward into the pass thumbs down, ok?
Into the pass, thumbs down.
Again.
Into the pass, thumbs down, ok?
Now, a regular pass, thumbs down, ok?
And you get it to him.
Nice chest pass.
Ok.
Right in the chest.
Thumbs down, forward.
Forward.
I'll step back, same thing.
You want to step into the pass.
Create momentum as you pass the ball, ok?
Chest pass, right.
Extend, good.
So then I'll step back some more, this here is the lengthy chest pass.
Chest pass.
Right.
You're coming down, transition, your man cuts, you hit him with a chest pass.
Bulls-eye right on his chest.
Couple of dribbles, hit him, chest pass, right?
Its real smooth, just nonchalant, you come down step through, chest pass.
Just hit him right there, he dribbles, comes down, man cuts to the basket, chest pass, right?
That there is pro conditioning drills chest pass defense.